Laurens van den Brule

Location: Singapore Nationality: Netherlands Email: I.vdbrule@gmail.com Mobile: +65 8282 8253



Qualifications

Business Economics and Finance (Master) at Rotterdam School of Management - Erasmus University, The Netherlands, 2003

 International Management (Bachelor) at Hogeschool van Utrecht, The Netherlands, 1999)

Key Skills

- Program and Project Portfolio Management (PMP certified)
- Lean Six Sigma (Black Belt IASSC)
- Proven Business Collaboration
- Business Strategy & Change Management
- Business Process Management Expert
- Communications & Stakeholder Mgmt.
- Business Transformation
- End-to-End Processes (O2C, M2D & H2R)
- Continuous Improvement (BPR)
- Strategy Execution & Performance Mgmt.
- Steering Committee Facilitation

Profile

Laurens is certified in Lean Six Sigma (BB), Program and Project Management Professional (PMP) and an expert in Business Process Management (BPM).

He has over 10 years' experience in Global Business Transformation, Change Management, Management Consulting, Strategy Execution, Operational Efficiency, Shared Service In- and Outsourcing. Laurens has Business Acumen and experience working across a multitude of industry sectors including; FMCG, Retail, Energy & Utilities, Government, Natural Resources, Banking and International Education.

During internal and external roles in Consulting and Global Leadership Roles Laurens implemented challenging and complex initiatives to deliver real business transformation, organisational change and continuous improvement. These initiatives were often to support complex change initiatives including technology implementation with tight timelines and cultural differences.

Date: 02/10/17

Career History

International Baccalaureate (Education provider), Singapore	01/2014 - to date
Global Manager – Business Process Management	
Litmus Group (Managing Consulting), Singapore	11/2008 – 12/2013
Managing Consultant	
Siegwerk Asia Pacific Pte Ltd (Packaging Ink), Singapore	03/2008 - 11/2008
Finance/Project Manager	
Arcadis Bouw & Vastgoed (Real Estate & Infrastructure), The Netherlands	01/2004 - 11/2007
Financial Analyst/Controller	
Rabobank (Banking), The Netherlands	02/2000 - 12/2003
Stock Order & Customer Services Executive	
DTB (Business Planning), The Netherlands	09/1998 - 03/1999
Business Plan Executive	

Project History (Cor	nsulting - Litmus Group)
-----------------------------	--------------------------

03/2013 - 09/2013	Leading Retail Company
	Regional Supply Chian & Target Operating Model Program – APAC
06/2012 - 03/2013	Energy & Utilities Company
	Business Transformation & ERP Implementation Project – Singapore
01/2012 - 06/2012	Leading Global Manufacturing and Distribution Organisation (FMCG)
	Global Alignment Project – Singapore
07/2011 – 12/2011	Energy & Utilities Company
	Business Case & Benefits Realisation Project – Australia
10/2009 – 07/2011	Leading Global Manufacturing and Distribution Organisation (FMCG)
	Business Process Management & ERP Implementation Program – APAC
04/2009 - 09/2009	Membership & Accountancy Company
	Business Process Review (CS & FS) Project – Australia
03/2008 - 06/2008	Packaging Ink Company
	IT data merger Project – Malaysia
07/2008 – 10/2008	Packaging Ink Company
	Performance Management Project – Malaysia

International Baccalaureate (Singapore)

01/2014 - now (3.5 years)

Global Education provider - Global role

Job Description:

In this position, I was tasked to support the Singapore Office and IB organisation to promote Business Process Management and contribute to overall success of ongoing projects. Additionally, I was tasked to standardise current ways of working across functional domains. One of the mayor projects was an implementation of Oracle R12 and leading an initiative to bring back In-House the Finance function (AP/AR & CO) as well as recruiting a new Business Process Team globally.

Role and Contribution:

Global Business Process Manager, responsible for:

- Lead enterprise wide Business Process Redesign in compliance with PMP
- Lead Finance In-Sourcing for Payables and Receivables Departments
- Drive Finance best practices & Process Adherence
- Organize Continuous Process Improvement Program across all Business Units
- Support ORACLE upgrade & Expense system implementation
- Introduce BPM vision, Roadmap and Central Process Asset
- Lead IB Operating Model thinking (supported by BPMS tools)
- Deliver Stakeholder & Steering Committee Communications & Meetings Facilitation
- Enterprise Change Management of BAU process initiatives (sprints not projects)
- Develop of BPR approach and conduct/facilitate workshops
- Performance Management of Team & Linking Organisation Goals to Departments & Roles

The Litmus Group (Singapore)

03/2013 – 09/2013 (6 months) Dairy Farms International

Regional Supply Chian & Target Operating Model Program - APAC region

Project Description:

This program was a review of ERP implementations in 2 APAC countries and documentation of country processes. At the same time the goal of the project was to streamline business processes and rationalise the disparate and bespoke systems in place, providing a Target Operating Model (Buy, Move and Sell) and identifying process improvements such as SAP utilising Retail best practices.

Role and Contribution:

Engagement Manager (across SAP Retail, BPM and Process Improvement work streams), responsible for:

- Identification and documentation of country processes, Problem Statement & Problem Solution regarding Demand Planning, Distribution Centre/Inventory Management, Vendor Performance Management (SAP Best Practice)
- Documentation of Role-based design & actual system usage (SAP Re-documentation)
- Introduction of Target Operating Model
- Stakeholder & Communication Management and overall Project Management
- Development of Process Commonality scorecards (Template deviation)
- Facilitation and execution of Current State assessment

06/2012 – 03/2013 (9 months) **Singapore Power**

Business Transformation & ERP Implementation Project - Singapore

Project Description:

This leading Singaporean Utilities company is undertaking a Business Transformation (BPR) project and introducing "new ways of working" for its Transmission and Distribution business. This covers all functional areas and processes for both Electricity and Gas. The objectives of this multi-year initiative are to establish common ways of working making use of automation, paperless and utilising the Enterprise Asset Management module & functionality.

Role and Contribution:

Engagement Manager (across Gas & Electricity business for Transmission & Distribution), responsible for:

- Advice and guidance on project approach, scheduling, deliverables and project timelines and overall project progress
- Stakeholder & Change Management and Deliverables Management (quality & delivery on time)
- Facilitation of key sessions/workshops with Steering Committee and Senior Stakeholders
- Management of internal and external project delivery team activities and interdependencies with ongoing projects and initiatives

01/2012 – 06/2012 (6 months) **Unilever Asia Pacific**

Global Alignment Project – Singapore

Project Description:

This leading FMCG is undertaking an alignment of global, regional and country process hierarchies to establish a singular global process model. The objectives of this initiative are to establish common ways of working, a single process model, enhanced reporting and reduced costs.

Role and Contribution:

Engagement Manager, responsible for:

- Management of the project delivery team (BPM for SAP deployment)
- Integration of Risk Management Framework into UAPL Process Framework
- Relationship Management with global and regional stakeholders
- Project Status Reporting & Ensuring Gateway Entry and Exit Criteria were met IFOT
- Advice and guidance on impacts from the global alignment on regional and country initiatives

07/2011 – 12/2011 (6 months) **Hydro Tasmania**

ERP Implementation & Business Case - Australia

Project Description:

Supported Hydro Tasmania which is an energy generation and distribution company in undertaking a full fledge implementation of an ERP system from Business Case through RFP and ERP Implementation (SAP). The objective of the project phase I was engaged for was to demonstrate the business case and financial viability of the project including project costing, business benefits and Expected Value over a ten year period. Critical for this was to present a financial model which shows the different complex business scenarios when assumptions or inputs of the model are changed with a high level of detail.

Role and Contribution:

Team Lead - Financial Modelling and Business Benefits, responsible for:

- Responsible for Business Case development and Financial Modelling (NPV calculation)
- Finance lead during the RFP process to identify System Integrator for ERP implementation
- Benefits Identification and developing a Business Realisation Framework including Benefit Drivers, Business Change Impact & Benefit Ownership

10/2009 – 07/2011 (2,5 years) Unilever Asia Pacific

Business Process Management Program - APAC

Project Description:

This leading FMCG Company implemented SAP across the APAC region with in total 9 releases for more than 25 countries costing hundreds of millions of dollars in total. The objectives of our role within this program of work were to establish and maintain a central process asset including country process variants sustainably. This included creating a template for particular business operations, country variants, process governance, and change management in a collaborative manner with PMO to ensure we work in synch. The work streams involved were Process Documentation, Country Process Maintenance, Process Governance, Process Maintenance, Testing and Training. Examples of benefits delivered: Inventory/Demand Visibility, Improved In-Full-on-Time Delivery (IFOT), Reduced Inventory levels and Introduction of Purchasing/Production & Distribution Planning across Unilever One Supply Chain.

Role and Contribution:

Engagement Manager, responsible for:

- Introduction of Business Process Asset and Regional Template
- BPM Design & Introduction using Process Driven SAP Methodology (PDSAP)
- Introduction and maintenance of Process Governance and Change Control (CR dashboard)
- Support implementation of SAP SCM rapid deployment/SAP APO
- Support FICO Process Areas & Drive Process Alignment
- Change Management and Deliverables Management (quality & delivery on time)
- Integration of Testing & Automatic Test Script Creation/updates using SAP Solution Manager
- Facilitation of key sessions/workshops with Steering Committee
- Coordination of delivery team activities with related projects and initiatives

04/2009 – 09/2009 (6 months) **CPA Australia**

Business Process Review (CS & FS) Project – Australia

Project Description:

This membership firm is undertaking a transformation of how they interact with their members and how they deliver accounting courses and diplomas through their existing Customer Relations Management system. The objectives of our role within this program of work were to document current state ways of working and current system usage with special detail to system requirements and improvement opportunities. This program of work required exceptional stakeholder management skills, ability to work under high pressure while at the same time being sensitive to issues between management and employees.

Role and Contribution:

Business Process Analyst, responsible for:

- Facilitation of workshops and Process mapping in detail
- Change Management and Deliverables Management (documentation)
- Internal communication and Business Process Management principles

Siegwerk Asia Pacific Pte Ltd Career History

03/2008 – 11/2008 (8 months) Siegwerk Asia Pacific Pte Ltd (Packaging Ink)

Role and Contribution:

Finance/Project Manager, responsible for:

- Member of APAC Finance team and reporting directly to the regional CFO.
- Managing data merger project in Malaysia (Combining 2 accounting systems).
- Defining and implementing of Key Performance Indicators as well as data input in close collaboration with the regional and local Supply Chain Mangers.

Arcadis Bouw & Vastgoed Career History

01/2004 – 11/2007 (3,5 years) Arcadis Bouw & Vastgoed (Real Estate & Infrastructure)

Financial Analyst – Amersfoort (The Netherlands)

Role and Contribution:

Finance Manager/Controller, responsible for:

- Reporting directly to management on project status, results, budgets and forecasts.
- Budgeting and cost management of large projects. Responsible for customer relations and financial planning of cash flow (yearly turnover in excess of € 10 M per year).
- Creating project management standards such as cost-calculation systems, scheduling and tracking of business developments (order intake, work in progress, Human Resource development).
- Implementation of changes such as procedures for Sarbanes-Oxley/IFRS accounting standards, responsible for preparing, organizing and supervising during audits (Span of control 80).

Rabobank Career History

02/2000 - 12/2003 (3 years) Rabobank Netherlands

Stock Order Line – Utrecht (The Netherlands)

Role and Contribution:

Member of Rabobank Order line team, responsible for:

- Processing of stock market transactions to be sent to European and American stock markets.
- Customer Relations: interaction with customers on order status or newly introduced products and services.

DTB Career History

09/1998 – 03/1999 (6 months) Direct Toepasbare Bestuurskunde

Business Plan Advisor - Baarn (The Netherlands)

Internship Description:

This was an internship to my Bachelor International Management – one of the 2 internships needed to have the profile for preparation for the job market and be hands-on. During my internship I completed Business Plans from start to finish for 2 medium sized organisations. One company was an electro technical service company while the other was an FMCG company manufacturing bakery products.

CURRICULUM VITAE

Role and Contribution:

Member of DTB service delivery team, responsible for:

- Internship at the Dutch Centre for Business Planning (DTB).
- Internal training of all material used by DTB and assisting with informational courses.
- Business Development: working closely with management teams to draw up 3 year business plans for 2 organisations & facilitation of workshops/training sessions.

Education

RSM Erasmus University Rotterdam (09/2000-09/2003)

Rotterdam, the Netherlands

- Master of Science (Faculty of Economics and Business Economics)
- Majors: Business Economics and Finance
- Core subjects: Business Valuation, Finance, Risk Management, Micro- & Macroeconomics, Accounting, Fiscal Economics, Finance & Investments, Statistics and Research Methods & Techniques
- Additional subjects: Organisation Management and Organisational Structure, Commercial Policy and Strategy, Business Administration, Management Accounting and Financial Accounting
- Thesis "Private Company Discount and valuing privately held companies" completed in 2007

College of Utrecht (09/1995-09/1999)

Utrecht, the Netherlands

Date: 02/10/17

- Bachelor Degree (Faculty of Economics and Management)
- Majors: International Management and Commercial Economics.
- Core subjects: Commercial Economics, Marketing Research, and Export Management.
- Additional subjects: General Economics, Statistics, Business Organisation, Business Administration, European Business Education, Sociology, Communication, English, German and Spanish.
- Thesis "Business and Internet" completed in 1999.

Computer & IT Skills

Microsoft Office: Full comprehension

ARIS & BPM tools: Full comprehension & Lean Six Sigma Certified (IASSC)

SAP/Oracle: Core modules understanding

ITIL/TOGAF/TOM: Full comprehension

Project Management: PMP certified